<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome on As We May Yet Think</title>
    <link>https://vmsmith.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome on As We May Yet Think</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:31:34 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vmsmith.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Supabase Architecture</title>
      <link>https://vmsmith.github.io/decisions/251205-supabase-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:31:34 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmsmith.github.io/decisions/251205-supabase-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;single-supabase-project-with-future-separation-path&#34;&gt;Single Supabase Project with Future Separation Path&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the initial development of personal Moneypenny, CTL Moneypenny, and Cletho, we will use a single Supabase project to simplify operations and control costs. To preserve future flexibility, each application will be architected as a self-contained module within that shared project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This design includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A dedicated Postgres schema for each app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Isolated storage buckets or folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separate Postgres roles and RLS policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrations grouped or prefixed by application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No cross-schema dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By enforcing these boundaries from the outset, each app can be cleanly extracted into its own Supabase project later with minimal friction—primarily a matter of exporting its schema, data, storage assets, and configuration. This approach balances near-term simplicity with long-term architectural optionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Cognitive Decline</title>
      <link>https://vmsmith.github.io/stray-voltage/251205/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:31:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmsmith.github.io/stray-voltage/251205/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was an article in the December 2025 issue of The Atlantic that talked about how use of AI can cause cognitive decline (&amp;ldquo;The People Outsourcing Their Thinking to AI&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One idea to prevent that was to have the application to tell users to take a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another idea, related to Cletho, would be to have the application &amp;ldquo;gently&amp;rdquo; suggest to the user that they think about how to write a better prompt. Do this in a way that nudges the user towards applying/developing their critical thinking skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A First Look at Memory</title>
      <link>https://vmsmith.github.io/blog/251205-memory-architecture-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmsmith.github.io/blog/251205-memory-architecture-intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A key to Moneypenny is memory management. An AI assistant is only as useful as what it remembers, what it forgets, and how gracefully it moves between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into memory itself, I want to distinguish between a program and a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;program&lt;/strong&gt; is an ongoing activity that coordinates multiple efforts in pursuit of a larger, strategic aim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It may not have a fixed end date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its outputs are capabilities rather than one-off deliverables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Success means: “Did we achieve the long-term benefits we intended?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;project&lt;/strong&gt;, by contrast, is aimed at producing a specific outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Origins of Moneypenny</title>
      <link>https://vmsmith.github.io/blog/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 20:54:21 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmsmith.github.io/blog/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The original Moneypenny was meant to be an AI executive assistant to help manage the large amount of information associated with Cletho development. The personal Moneypenny I am developing here is meant to help me manage my own life and the my goals and objectives within it. The initial specific functions of the application are to assist in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing my calendar (which may include connections to other calendars).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintaining a &amp;ldquo;To Do&amp;rdquo; list of things I want or need to do, and sending reminders for specified items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing and managing project plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping a time stamped, searchable journal of specified things I do over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping an time stamped, searchable log of ideas I come up with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recording important decisions, with rationale and context, in an time stamped, searchable log.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintaining an &amp;ldquo;Open Loops&amp;rdquo; list of things other people are responsible for doing, such as returning lent items, doing things they said they&amp;rsquo;d do, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indexing digital artifacts, to wit, keep a record of where media articles, key discussion topics, document summaries, etc. can be found.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holding and publishing long-term reminders, e.g., such-and-such a subscription is expiring next month, Delaware taxes are due in a month, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing topical research on subjects of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summarizing documents and identifying key points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refining the Site Structure and First Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://vmsmith.github.io/log/entry-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmsmith.github.io/log/entry-002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I refined several parts of the new Hugo site as I continued building the
public-facing workspace for the Moneypenny and Cletho projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key updates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published my first real blog post and verified the local → GitHub Pages
workflow end-to-end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up the site navigation by keeping only the sections that make sense
right now: &lt;strong&gt;Blog&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Log&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Architecture&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Decisions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configured the homepage so that it no longer shows the most recent blog post.
The homepage now serves purely as an introduction rather than a blog feed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a proper &lt;code&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; to keep build artifacts like &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; out of
version control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensured the GitHub Actions workflow remains clean and deploys correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is now significantly cleaner, easier to navigate, and better aligned
with the narrative and functional goals of the project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Setup and Deployment</title>
      <link>https://vmsmith.github.io/log/entry-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vmsmith.github.io/log/entry-001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I published the new public-facing Hugo site that will serve as the working
log and narrative record for the Cletho and Moneypenny projects. This marks the
beginning of the development log.
+++
date = &amp;lsquo;2025-11-27T20:54:51-05:00&amp;rsquo;
draft = true
title = &amp;lsquo;Entry 001&amp;rsquo;
+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
